<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jason Scheirer on the Internet on Jason Scheirer</title>
    <link>https://www.jasonscheirer.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Jason Scheirer on the Internet on Jason Scheirer</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 Jan 2021 12:11:45 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.jasonscheirer.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Pinebook Pro: The Tinkering Laptop</title>
      <link>https://www.jasonscheirer.com/weblog/pinebook-pro-the-tinkering-laptop/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jan 2021 12:11:45 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jasonscheirer.com/weblog/pinebook-pro-the-tinkering-laptop/</guid>
      <description>As the parent of an almost three year old, I don&amp;rsquo;t get much time to myself, and I&amp;rsquo;ve given up on video games that don&amp;rsquo;t have playtimes under 15 minutes (that discounts anything with load times or cutscenes). In my spare time I have to find other things to do that are low impact and can be cut into small amounts of time.
I&amp;rsquo;ve taken to watching a lot of retrocomputing stuff on YouTube, which has inspired me to tinker with old software and resource constrained devices.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Dingus Chromebook still works</title>
      <link>https://www.jasonscheirer.com/weblog/chromebook-still-works/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2020 01:11:45 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jasonscheirer.com/weblog/chromebook-still-works/</guid>
      <description>So I bought that dang Chromebook over three years ago at this point and it keeps chugging on. Google has continued to ship OS updates (which I only notice as weird, arbitrary UI changes) and I can still use it to code but its main purpose now is its new life: ChromeOS runs Android apps pretty well, so I put an SD card full of movies on it and play them via VLC for my kid.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Five Years in the Bay Area</title>
      <link>https://www.jasonscheirer.com/weblog/five-years-in-the-bay/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Feb 2020 06:25:45 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jasonscheirer.com/weblog/five-years-in-the-bay/</guid>
      <description>February 8th marks the fifth anniversary of me moving to the Bay Area to work for tech startups. In restrospect it&amp;rsquo;s been a great experience despite it being the Bay Area.
Culture Living in the Inland Empire, I was an hour away from LA and all that culture, but I never bothered doing it. Living 5 miles outside of San Francisco has mean the City is a constant part of my life: restaurants, concerts, museums, lots of things I could have theoretically done more of in SoCal but never bothered to.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Own your infrastructure</title>
      <link>https://www.jasonscheirer.com/weblog/own-your-infrastructure/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2020 16:45:45 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jasonscheirer.com/weblog/own-your-infrastructure/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been sharecropping on Amazon&amp;rsquo;s server farms since I moved to the Bay Area 5 years ago. That is, every startup I&amp;rsquo;ve worked for has utilized AWS (and sometimes GCP or Azure in addition).
This started out great for my career because I have not built a server machine from parts out since I was in college and I could use all my developer muscles to be operations person.
However, when you&amp;rsquo;re on-call, you no longer own your uptime.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello, World</title>
      <link>https://www.jasonscheirer.com/weblog/hello-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2020 10:18:17 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jasonscheirer.com/weblog/hello-world/</guid>
      <description>I should probably start blogging again.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python Meetup Talk - 2019-10-09</title>
      <link>https://www.jasonscheirer.com/weblog/python-meetup-sf-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2019 10:18:17 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jasonscheirer.com/weblog/python-meetup-sf-2019/</guid>
      <description>I gave a short (~10) minute talk on preparing to move to microservices at the Python meetup in San Francisco.
The main points:
 We all start out with a monolith The monolith never fully goes away That&amp;rsquo;s fine Scope out a new project to make your first microservice Pull out a relatively isolated piece of code in the monolith to make your next microservice  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Turn a Chromebook into the ULTIMATE GOLANG/PYTHON DEVELOPER MACHINE</title>
      <link>https://www.jasonscheirer.com/weblog/make-a-chromebook-a-developer-machine/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Dec 2016 01:11:45 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jasonscheirer.com/weblog/make-a-chromebook-a-developer-machine/</guid>
      <description>This is a recycled post from my tumblr weblog
Ha ha ha just lying the real title should be
Turning a Piece of Shit Chromebook into a Good Enough Development Machine Because You&amp;rsquo;re Unemployed and Feel Like An Ass Trying to Justify Spending $2000 on a God Damned Macbook so You Wound Up Buying a Chromebook Instead Anyway, I&amp;rsquo;m unemployed because of reasons and figured there were better things to do with the credit limit on my credit card than spend $2000 on a Macbook, so I bought one of the highest rated Chromebooks at my &amp;ldquo;willing to pay this much&amp;rdquo; price point: the Chromebook C100P.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What I Like About My New Job</title>
      <link>https://www.jasonscheirer.com/weblog/things-i-like-about-my-new-job/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 May 2015 19:55:10 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jasonscheirer.com/weblog/things-i-like-about-my-new-job/</guid>
      <description>This is a recycled post from my tumblr weblog. I&amp;rsquo;ve since had three other jobs, but a lot of what I like still rings true 5 years later in 2020.
Please note I am contractually prohibited from saying what I don&amp;rsquo;t like about most of my prior employers so don&amp;rsquo;t expect any negative posts.
I&amp;rsquo;ve gone from developer at a large software corporation in the suburbs of Southern California to being a developer at a startup in SoMa in San Francisco.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stupid simple API reference for bottle.py web services</title>
      <link>https://www.jasonscheirer.com/weblog/bottle-introspection/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Mar 2012 22:11:11 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jasonscheirer.com/weblog/bottle-introspection/</guid>
      <description>I have a stupid json-only REST API I implemented in bottle.py. This introspects the default app, gives a dumb readout that should act as an adequate reference for discovery:
@bottle.route(&amp;#39;/&amp;#39;) def index(): bottle.response.content_type = &amp;#39;text/plain&amp;#39; return (&amp;#34;=== API REFERENCE ===\n&amp;#34; + &amp;#34;\n&amp;#34;.join(x[&amp;#39;rule&amp;#39;] for x in bottle.app().routes)) </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>C&#43;&#43; is not so bad</title>
      <link>https://www.jasonscheirer.com/weblog/cpp-is-ok/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Sep 2010 16:45:45 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jasonscheirer.com/weblog/cpp-is-ok/</guid>
      <description>For as much shit as I like to talk about C++, I sure can get a lot done quite efficiently in it.
I read an interview with Bjarne a while back and he said C++’s most important feature was destructors. After thinking about it, yeah, they are pretty awesome and I’ve been using the with statement for the same tightly scoped data lifetime in Python.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I don’t really use OSX anymore</title>
      <link>https://www.jasonscheirer.com/weblog/osx-less-and-less/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Feb 2010 01:15:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jasonscheirer.com/weblog/osx-less-and-less/</guid>
      <description>I have two desktop systems, side-by-side: an Intel Mac Mini and an Intel 21&amp;quot; iMac. The Mini runs Leopard and the iMac runs Ubuntu Karmic Koala, and I find myself completely satisfied with the Linux desktop, and switch back to OSX as an auxiliary rather than as my primary.
I started on Debian back in 1999. I wanted to get into Linux, but both Red Hat and SuSE were a little hard to get going for beginners, and the packages supplied were always a weird grab bag of old and new.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://www.jasonscheirer.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2000 08:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jasonscheirer.com/about/</guid>
      <description>I am Jason Scheirer, a completely unremarkable software developer in the Bay Area initially from the Inland Empire. I have been programming since I was in elementary school. I got my first job writing &amp;ldquo;web applications&amp;rdquo; as a junior in high school and have been doing it ever since. I have been out of school since 2005, writing software full time ever since.
The theme for this weblog is a fork of smol.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
