<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jason Scheirer on the Internet on Jason Scheirer</title>
    <link>https://www.jasonscheirer.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Jason Scheirer on the Internet on Jason Scheirer</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2022 00:00:00 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.jasonscheirer.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Modern Python has Changed How I Code</title>
      <link>https://www.jasonscheirer.com/weblog/modern-python-has-changed-how-i-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2022 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jasonscheirer.com/weblog/modern-python-has-changed-how-i-code/</guid>
      <description>I can&amp;rsquo;t understate the importance of how much the following have changed and improved the way I write Python and have confidence in its correctness:
Continuous Integration Black Dataclasses Mypy Type Hints Continuous Integration This isn&amp;rsquo;t particularly new to me (or the industry), but a good CI workflow that runs tests and linting on every commit pushed to the repo tracker gives confidence that the code is clean to merge into the main branch.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python as a Language is Unescabably Coupled with its Implementation Part 1: LET&#39;S DO DUMB SHIT WITH THE GC</title>
      <link>https://www.jasonscheirer.com/weblog/python-will-never-be-decoupled-from-its-implementation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Apr 2021 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jasonscheirer.com/weblog/python-will-never-be-decoupled-from-its-implementation/</guid>
      <description>There is a convenient but untrue fiction about Python that the language specification is somehow cleanroom and CPython is actually &amp;ldquo;just an implementation.&amp;rdquo;
This has always been false, and harmful at best.
Look at __dict__. Near every Python object has a dictionary that fuels and consumes it. All your dotted getters are mere passthroughs for dot __getitem__ers.
Another fun thing is the leaking of implementation details in Bad Ways. Here&amp;rsquo;s something you can do but should not do, lest I find out where you live and poop in your mailbox:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>__all__ is a Sacred Space and you Murderous Goblins are all Profaning it</title>
      <link>https://www.jasonscheirer.com/weblog/dunder-all-is-a-sacred-space-and-everyone-is-profaning-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Mar 2021 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jasonscheirer.com/weblog/dunder-all-is-a-sacred-space-and-everyone-is-profaning-it/</guid>
      <description>Let me spell something out for you trickster-meanies:
# HELLO I AM thingy.py __all__ = [X, Y, Z] X = True Y = True Z = True Reasonable, right?
&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; from thingy import * Traceback (most recent call last): File &amp;#34;&amp;lt;stdin&amp;gt;&amp;#34;, line 1, in &amp;lt;module&amp;gt; File &amp;#34;/Users/scheirer/thingy.py&amp;#34;, line 1, in &amp;lt;module&amp;gt; __all__ = [X, Y, Z] NameError: name &amp;#39;X&amp;#39; is not defined Python is older than my son (who is 3) and yet you abuse it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ZPL-O-Rama Part 5: Postscript</title>
      <link>https://www.jasonscheirer.com/weblog/zpl-o-rama-part-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jasonscheirer.com/weblog/zpl-o-rama-part-5/</guid>
      <description>End product Please disregard the poor camera placement, it has since been fixed.
Thinking Back, It Was All So Simple Now we have the system up and running, let&amp;rsquo;s talk random obstacles and next steps. This sis something of an epilogue to the saga, as it&amp;rsquo;s a lit of small things that accrued while working on the project
Networks are slow and the dual tier service thing is bad, actually I initially chose to run a service on the Nginx server that then called to a service running on the RPi.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ZPL-O-Rama Part 4: The Hardware</title>
      <link>https://www.jasonscheirer.com/weblog/zpl-o-rama-part-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jasonscheirer.com/weblog/zpl-o-rama-part-4/</guid>
      <description>Hardware The RPi The Raspberry Pi is a (I think) Pi 3 with Wifi I found in the garage with a cheap clear acrylic case. It might have been a RetroPie rig in a prior life? Or one I was &amp;ldquo;gonna get around to&amp;rdquo; doing something with and finally did?
Then for this project I bought a Raspberry Pi camera and a small acrylic case for it, too.
The Printer The printer is a hefty boi, a Zebra something or other.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ZPL-O-Rama Part 3: Software</title>
      <link>https://www.jasonscheirer.com/weblog/zpl-o-rama-part-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 03:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jasonscheirer.com/weblog/zpl-o-rama-part-3/</guid>
      <description>Running the software Frontend server The frontend has three responsibilities:
Display information Perform access control (don&amp;rsquo;t let strangers on the internet print out jobs) Forward appropriate calls to the backend I&amp;rsquo;m using Go&amp;rsquo;s base templates for dynamic content, the Echo framework for the webapp endpoints, and plain old bare bones modern javascripto for the scripting stuff with no polyfills, no build environments, no minifiers, and boy does it feel good.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ZPL-O-Rama Part 2: Concepts and Architecture</title>
      <link>https://www.jasonscheirer.com/weblog/zpl-o-rama-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 02:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jasonscheirer.com/weblog/zpl-o-rama-part-2/</guid>
      <description>Problem Space To automate the process of printing and reporting back a ZPL payload, we need:
A way to get the ZPL from the user A way to send the ZPL to a printer A way to take a picture A way to send it back to the user A way to get the ZPL from the user A web service makes sense here. We want an API or a frontend (or both) to send the ZPL along and check its printing status.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ZPL-O-Rama Part 1: A personal/work project (Introduction)</title>
      <link>https://www.jasonscheirer.com/weblog/zpl-o-rama-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jasonscheirer.com/weblog/zpl-o-rama-part-1/</guid>
      <description>Introduction In my spare time on weekends in between errands and mornings before everyone wakes up, I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on a little project I&amp;rsquo;ve been having a lot of fun with: ZPL-O-Rama.
The Problem A large part of my employer&amp;rsquo;s line of business is creating shipping labels, and a large number of those aren&amp;rsquo;t simply printed images, but printed on very high volume, heavy duty, industrial grade printers using a proprietary language called ZPL.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Shanling Q1 Media Player</title>
      <link>https://www.jasonscheirer.com/weblog/shanling-q1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jasonscheirer.com/weblog/shanling-q1/</guid>
      <description>Introduction A while ago I was bored with the Mechanical Keyboard rabbit hole and started looking into other, equally strange rabbit holes to dive into. At around the same time I hit my iPod Classic&amp;rsquo;s 160GB limit. I&amp;rsquo;m not yet ready to hack it up to have bigger storage: I plan to keep it in working &amp;ldquo;original&amp;rdquo; condition as it may find a better home in the future with some collector who is better at soldering than I.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SFTP is still around and that&#39;s OK</title>
      <link>https://www.jasonscheirer.com/weblog/sftp-is-still-around-and-thats-ok/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Feb 2021 08:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jasonscheirer.com/weblog/sftp-is-still-around-and-thats-ok/</guid>
      <description>So it&amp;rsquo;s 2021 and about the entirety of my job is integrating third party systems with internal ones, which then reach out to other third-party services.
A lot of stuff uses SFTP still. In this day and age anything not on HTTP seems barbaric, but SFTP does have its advantages.
SFTP is format agnostic This goes for HTTP as well, but you need to correctly set headers, and there&amp;rsquo;s a constant, incessant push for change for change&amp;rsquo;s sake.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You Don&#39;t Need to Make That Temporary File, Dude</title>
      <link>https://www.jasonscheirer.com/weblog/dont-use-tempfiles/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Feb 2021 08:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jasonscheirer.com/weblog/dont-use-tempfiles/</guid>
      <description>This was initially a blog post I wrote on my employer&amp;rsquo;s internal system, but it&amp;rsquo;s interestingly useful and it doesn&amp;rsquo;t contain any trade secrets so I figure I&amp;rsquo;ll share.
A common pattern that seems obvious when you need to shuttle data around in file form is to use a temporary file against the filesystem using the tempfile module.
You very seldom ACTUALLY need to do this. The BytesIO class follows the exact same protocol, the file protocol, so any API that accepts a &amp;ldquo;file-like object&amp;rdquo; will accept an in-memory piece of information in addition to a file on disk.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trying out Rectangle</title>
      <link>https://www.jasonscheirer.com/weblog/trying-out-rectangle/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Feb 2021 10:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jasonscheirer.com/weblog/trying-out-rectangle/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been using the Rectangle window manager for mac for the last couple of weeks and it&amp;rsquo;s been the most helpful thing since Mission Control (and setting up a hot corner to activate it).
I&amp;rsquo;ve tried to use full tiling managers before but I&amp;rsquo;ve found it difficult because 1) Irregularly sized window totally mess up the flow, 2) I am so used to the WIMP paradigm, including moving windows around so I have only been semi-functional with and 3) really weird shortcuts I have to memorize.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The 2020s and the Post-Office World</title>
      <link>https://www.jasonscheirer.com/weblog/the-post-office-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Feb 2021 07:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jasonscheirer.com/weblog/the-post-office-world/</guid>
      <description>I moved to the Bay Area 6 years ago after stubbornly refusing to for over a decade before because I wanted to be in the middle of the world of software. 2020 made some of that luster wear off.
Our office closed at the end of March, 2020, for what was scheduled to be 2 months, which eventually stretched out into over 6 months, until finally we were told to clean off our desks by Thanksgiving as we were permanently remote.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pinebook Pro: The Tinkering Laptop</title>
      <link>https://www.jasonscheirer.com/weblog/pinebook-pro-the-tinkering-laptop/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jan 2021 12:11:45 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jasonscheirer.com/weblog/pinebook-pro-the-tinkering-laptop/</guid>
      <description>As the parent of an almost three year old, I don&amp;rsquo;t get much time to myself, and I&amp;rsquo;ve given up on video games that don&amp;rsquo;t have playtimes under 15 minutes (that discounts anything with load times or cutscenes). In my spare time I have to find other things to do that are low impact and can be cut into small amounts of time.
I&amp;rsquo;ve taken to watching a lot of retrocomputing stuff on YouTube, which has inspired me to tinker with old software and resource constrained devices.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Dingus Chromebook still works</title>
      <link>https://www.jasonscheirer.com/weblog/chromebook-still-works/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2020 01:11:45 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jasonscheirer.com/weblog/chromebook-still-works/</guid>
      <description>So I bought that dang Chromebook over three years ago at this point and it keeps chugging on. Google has continued to ship OS updates (which I only notice as weird, arbitrary UI changes) and I can still use it to code but its main purpose now is its new life: ChromeOS runs Android apps pretty well, so I put an SD card full of movies on it and play them via VLC for my kid.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Five Years in the Bay Area</title>
      <link>https://www.jasonscheirer.com/weblog/five-years-in-the-bay/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Feb 2020 06:25:45 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jasonscheirer.com/weblog/five-years-in-the-bay/</guid>
      <description>February 8th marks the fifth anniversary of me moving to the Bay Area to work for tech startups. In restrospect it&amp;rsquo;s been a great experience despite it being the Bay Area.
Culture Living in the Inland Empire, I was an hour away from LA and all that culture, but I never bothered doing it. Living 5 miles outside of San Francisco has mean the City is a constant part of my life: restaurants, concerts, museums, lots of things I could have theoretically done more of in SoCal but never bothered to.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Own your infrastructure</title>
      <link>https://www.jasonscheirer.com/weblog/own-your-infrastructure/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2020 16:45:45 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jasonscheirer.com/weblog/own-your-infrastructure/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been sharecropping on Amazon&amp;rsquo;s server farms since I moved to the Bay Area 5 years ago. That is, every startup I&amp;rsquo;ve worked for has utilized AWS (and sometimes GCP or Azure in addition).
This started out great for my career because I have not built a server machine from parts out since I was in college and I could use all my developer muscles to be operations person.
However, when you&amp;rsquo;re on-call, you no longer own your uptime.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello, World</title>
      <link>https://www.jasonscheirer.com/weblog/hello-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2020 10:18:17 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jasonscheirer.com/weblog/hello-world/</guid>
      <description>I should probably start blogging again.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python Meetup Talk - 2019-10-09</title>
      <link>https://www.jasonscheirer.com/weblog/python-meetup-sf-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2019 10:18:17 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jasonscheirer.com/weblog/python-meetup-sf-2019/</guid>
      <description>I gave a short (~10) minute talk on preparing to move to microservices at the Python meetup in San Francisco.
The main points:
We all start out with a monolith The monolith never fully goes away That&amp;rsquo;s fine Scope out a new project to make your first microservice Pull out a relatively isolated piece of code in the monolith to make your next microservice </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jumpbear: the Global Warming Bear</title>
      <link>https://www.jasonscheirer.com/weblog/jumpbear/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 May 2018 01:15:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jasonscheirer.com/weblog/jumpbear/</guid>
      <description>I wrote a handful of different things on my paternity leave, but one of the more interesting ones was this small TIC-80 game where you play a bear.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Turn a Chromebook into the ULTIMATE GOLANG/PYTHON DEVELOPER MACHINE</title>
      <link>https://www.jasonscheirer.com/weblog/make-a-chromebook-a-developer-machine/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Dec 2016 01:11:45 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jasonscheirer.com/weblog/make-a-chromebook-a-developer-machine/</guid>
      <description>This is a recycled post from my tumblr weblog
Ha ha ha just lying the real title should be
Turning a Piece of Shit Chromebook into a Good Enough Development Machine Because You&amp;rsquo;re Unemployed and Feel Like An Ass Trying to Justify Spending $2000 on a God Damned Macbook so You Wound Up Buying a Chromebook Instead Anyway, I&amp;rsquo;m unemployed because of reasons and figured there were better things to do with the credit limit on my credit card than spend $2000 on a Macbook, so I bought one of the highest rated Chromebooks at my &amp;ldquo;willing to pay this much&amp;rdquo; price point: the Chromebook C100P.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What I Like About My New Job</title>
      <link>https://www.jasonscheirer.com/weblog/things-i-like-about-my-new-job/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 May 2015 19:55:10 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jasonscheirer.com/weblog/things-i-like-about-my-new-job/</guid>
      <description>This is a recycled post from my tumblr weblog. I&amp;rsquo;ve since had three other jobs, but a lot of what I like still rings true 5 years later in 2020.
Please note I am contractually prohibited from saying what I don&amp;rsquo;t like about most of my prior employers so don&amp;rsquo;t expect any negative posts.
I&amp;rsquo;ve gone from developer at a large software corporation in the suburbs of Southern California to being a developer at a startup in SoMa in San Francisco.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stupid simple API reference for bottle.py web services</title>
      <link>https://www.jasonscheirer.com/weblog/bottle-introspection/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Mar 2012 22:11:11 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jasonscheirer.com/weblog/bottle-introspection/</guid>
      <description>I have a stupid json-only REST API I implemented in bottle.py. This introspects the default app, gives a dumb readout that should act as an adequate reference for discovery:
@bottle.route(&amp;#39;/&amp;#39;) def index(): bottle.response.content_type = &amp;#39;text/plain&amp;#39; return (&amp;#34;=== API REFERENCE ===\n&amp;#34; + &amp;#34;\n&amp;#34;.join(x[&amp;#39;rule&amp;#39;] for x in bottle.app().routes)) </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>C&#43;&#43; is not so bad</title>
      <link>https://www.jasonscheirer.com/weblog/cpp-is-ok/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Sep 2010 16:45:45 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jasonscheirer.com/weblog/cpp-is-ok/</guid>
      <description>For as much shit as I like to talk about C++, I sure can get a lot done quite efficiently in it.
I read an interview with Bjarne a while back and he said C++’s most important feature was destructors. After thinking about it, yeah, they are pretty awesome and I’ve been using the with statement for the same tightly scoped data lifetime in Python.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I don’t really use OSX anymore</title>
      <link>https://www.jasonscheirer.com/weblog/osx-less-and-less/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Feb 2010 01:15:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jasonscheirer.com/weblog/osx-less-and-less/</guid>
      <description>I have two desktop systems, side-by-side: an Intel Mac Mini and an Intel 21&amp;quot; iMac. The Mini runs Leopard and the iMac runs Ubuntu Karmic Koala, and I find myself completely satisfied with the Linux desktop, and switch back to OSX as an auxiliary rather than as my primary.
I started on Debian back in 1999. I wanted to get into Linux, but both Red Hat and SuSE were a little hard to get going for beginners, and the packages supplied were always a weird grab bag of old and new.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://www.jasonscheirer.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jasonscheirer.com/about/</guid>
      <description>I am Jason Scheirer, a completely unremarkable software developer in the Bay Area initially from the Inland Empire. A rough timeline of my life as a software engineer:
Start programming BASIC in elementary school, escalating to pirated QuickBasic and Turbo Pascal, as well as legal but squirrely DJGPP/RHIDE/Allegro Get a part-time job in late high school writing &amp;ldquo;web applications&amp;rdquo; Get bored in intro CS classes and change majors to Linguistics Decide that taking a full courseload is for suckers who like sleep and good grades and take on night classes for TESOL at the same time Backpedal and get as much CS coursework done as possible before hitting the unit limit for graduation, managing to squeeze in the minor just in time List about from company to company in SoCal writing software for 10 years, mostly Python/C, mostly geospatial adjacent Move to Bay Area and list about from startup to startup writing software for 6 years and counting, mostly Python A rough timeline of my entire life, including the future:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
