<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Engineering Virtues on Jason Scheirer</title>
    <link>https://www.jasonscheirer.com/engineering-virtues/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Engineering Virtues on Jason Scheirer</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 12:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.jasonscheirer.com/engineering-virtues/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>You Need to Break the Rules</title>
      <link>https://www.jasonscheirer.com/engineering-virtues/you-need-to-break-the-rules/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jasonscheirer.com/engineering-virtues/you-need-to-break-the-rules/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a short one: over the course of your job, you are going to need to operate outside of the range of your defined permissions and responsibilities. You should do this &lt;em&gt;sparingly&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;secretly&lt;/em&gt;. You should be able to operate outside of the system when you need to, and you need to know how to do it in non-obvious ways so you don&amp;rsquo;t get your escape hatches taken away from you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some benign examples of this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Occasionally merging a hotfix PR without code review&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Knowing a backdoor for read-only access to the prod database&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Being buddies with the devops team and being able to spin up new infra outside of roadmaps and plans&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Operating 100% within the rules is career death: you will not be able to move the needle if you spend all of your effort coloring within the lines. Rule following or not, you will be laid off when things get bad. Nobody gets promoted for good behavior, they get promoted for being well-liked. Alternately, judicious application of breaking the rules, if the results are good, will not result in you losing your job (unless you are not popular).&lt;/p&gt;
</description><category domain="https://www.jasonscheirer.com//tags/virtues">virtues</category>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Passively Transparent</title>
      <link>https://www.jasonscheirer.com/engineering-virtues/passively-transparent/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2025 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jasonscheirer.com/engineering-virtues/passively-transparent/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One thing that is important to me as an engineer that I don&amp;rsquo;t think I&amp;rsquo;ve seen put in writing is something I have distilled into the term &lt;em&gt;passively transparent&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It should be obvious to the people in leadership what is motivating you to work and what you are working on (transparency), and it should not require an on-demand effort on your part to communicate this to them (passive access).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You should also be transparent for the reason that you are setting a baseline of what you are expecting to share with your manager: if they feel like you aren&amp;rsquo;t giving good status it gives them tacit permission to ask &lt;em&gt;too many questions&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;questions that are inappropriately deep&lt;/em&gt;. Calibrate the level of communication by setting it yourself: keep your management at an arm&amp;rsquo;s length in how they use your time and attention. &amp;ldquo;I refer you to this query on GitHub, which you may access at any time&amp;rdquo; when someone asks about your deliverables should be a response you aspire for and your leadership accepts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A lot of the agile software movement and its offshoots attempt to codify and formalize processes of behavior that boil down to expressing these values:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;keep-track-of-what-you-are-working-on&#34;&gt;Keep Track Of What You Are Working On&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If a manager or peer wants to see what you are working on, they shouldn&amp;rsquo;t have to ask for a status update: they should be able to figure it out on their own at any time on demand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open a draft PR the &lt;em&gt;second&lt;/em&gt; you begin coding, push to it regularly. Hourly during standard hour, if you can.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Broadcast your current status on your issue tracking site: it is more work in the short run, but give you warm fuzzies (line go down on burndown) and lets you give high-value opportunities to course correct before going too far.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Keep tickets at a 1-3 working day granularity and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Move them along the started -&amp;gt; in progress -&amp;gt; finished pipeline quickly to telegraph to your management that you are working
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Independently&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;On the right things&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;At a reasonable pace.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;share-what-you-are-doing-with-others&#34;&gt;Share What You Are Doing With Others&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Set permissions by default to &lt;em&gt;commenter&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;editor&lt;/em&gt; on every document and web site you start.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Assume if someone is curious enough to want to know something that they are a stakeholder, whether they like it or not. Let them know. Pull them in.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Share everything: use public Slack channels. Private channels and DMs are for shit talking and performance reviews, not for day-to-day work.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;dont-let-_when_-something-happens-influence-_how_-and-_why_-it-happens-too-much&#34;&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t Let &lt;em&gt;When&lt;/em&gt; Something Happens Influence &lt;em&gt;How&lt;/em&gt; And &lt;em&gt;Why&lt;/em&gt; It Happens Too Much&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is something that has always mattered to me, doubly so with the forced async-by-default working world inflicted on us by the pandemic years and working with multi-time-zone teams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Make decisions (choose one end, these are opposite ends of a continuum):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As quickly as possible with minimal consensus but easy to change course on&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As late as possible with as long as reasonable to get input on&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;encourage-this-behavior-in-others&#34;&gt;Encourage This Behavior In Others&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One way to promote this way of working is to practice it yourself: when working in a team, engage with your peers with the expectation that they are working in a passively transparent manner themselves. A quick, no-expectations &amp;ldquo;I was reading your draft PR, looks good,&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;is there a Jira queue I&amp;rsquo;m not watching where you&amp;rsquo;re doing daily updates?&amp;rdquo; on Slack can do wonders in a non-forceful way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;be-an-iceberg&#34;&gt;Be An Iceberg&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When operating transparently, as the phrase goes, &lt;em&gt;don&amp;rsquo;t let your mouth write checks your ass can&amp;rsquo;t cash&lt;/em&gt;. Send along curated information that is a good summary of what you are doing, but be able to support it with research, opinion, or buy-in when pushed. Reveal enough to convey that you are a force, but do not reveal &lt;em&gt;everything&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do not operate at 100% capacity at all times, aim to operate at 80% so that when you &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; need to you can crank up your productivity in a sustainable way.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><category domain="https://www.jasonscheirer.com//tags/virtues">virtues</category>
      
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
