<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>software on Jason Scheirer</title>
    <link>https://www.jasonscheirer.com/tags/software/</link>
    <description>Recent content in software on Jason Scheirer</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 05:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.jasonscheirer.com/tags/software/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>ZPL-O-Rama Part 5: Postscript</title>
      <link>https://www.jasonscheirer.com/weblog/zpl-o-rama-part-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jasonscheirer.com/weblog/zpl-o-rama-part-5/</guid>
      <description>End product Please disregard the poor camera placement, it has since been fixed.
       Thinking Back, It Was All So Simple Now we have the system up and running, let&amp;rsquo;s talk random obstacles and next steps. This sis something of an epilogue to the saga, as it&amp;rsquo;s a lit of small things that accrued while working on the project
Networks are slow and the dual tier service thing is bad, actually I initially chose to run a service on the Nginx server that then called to a service running on the RPi.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ZPL-O-Rama Part 4: The Hardware</title>
      <link>https://www.jasonscheirer.com/weblog/zpl-o-rama-part-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jasonscheirer.com/weblog/zpl-o-rama-part-4/</guid>
      <description>Hardware The RPi The Raspberry Pi is a (I think) Pi 3 with Wifi I found in the garage with a cheap clear acrylic case. It might have been a RetroPie rig in a prior life? Or one I was &amp;ldquo;gonna get around to&amp;rdquo; doing something with and finally did?
Then for this project I bought a Raspberry Pi camera and a small acrylic case for it, too.
The Printer The printer is a hefty boi, a Zebra something or other.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ZPL-O-Rama Part 3: Concepts, Architecture, Software</title>
      <link>https://www.jasonscheirer.com/weblog/zpl-o-rama-part-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 03:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jasonscheirer.com/weblog/zpl-o-rama-part-3/</guid>
      <description>Let&amp;rsquo;s Talk Architecture The next thing I needed to do was plan out how this would work. I made a diagram to make sure I wasn&amp;rsquo;t missing anything.
   I&amp;rsquo;ll use Nginx at the edge to route to a frontend application. Then I&amp;rsquo;ll forward to a backend application which is running on my Raspberry pi which handles the printing/photography step.
Then, I&amp;rsquo;ll present the user a nice web service hosted on a machine on the cloud with a Real Internet IP where the user can log in, enter ZPL, and see the output.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ZPL-O-Rama Part 2: Concepts</title>
      <link>https://www.jasonscheirer.com/weblog/zpl-o-rama-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 02:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jasonscheirer.com/weblog/zpl-o-rama-part-2/</guid>
      <description>Problem Space To automate the process of printing and reporting back a ZPL payload, we need:
 A way to get the ZPL from the user A way to send the ZPL to a printer A way to take a picture A way to send it back to the user  A way to get the ZPL from the user A web service makes sense here. We want an API or a frontend (or both) to send the ZPL along and check its printing status.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ZPL-O-Rama Part 1: A personal/work project (Introduction)</title>
      <link>https://www.jasonscheirer.com/weblog/zpl-o-rama-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jasonscheirer.com/weblog/zpl-o-rama-part-1/</guid>
      <description>Introduction In my spare time on weekends in between errands and mornings before everyone wakes up, I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on a little project I&amp;rsquo;ve been having a lot of fun with: ZPL-O-Rama.
The Problem A large part of my employer&amp;rsquo;s line of business is creating shipping labels, and a large number of those aren&amp;rsquo;t simply printed images, but printed on very high volume, heavy duty, industrial grade printers using a proprietary language called ZPL.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
