<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Work on Jason Scheirer</title>
    <link>https://www.jasonscheirer.com/tags/work/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Work on Jason Scheirer</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.jasonscheirer.com/tags/work/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A Series of Vignettes From My Childhood and Early Career</title>
      <link>https://www.jasonscheirer.com/weblog/vignettes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jasonscheirer.com/weblog/vignettes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A short set of anecdotes, apropos of nothing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-death-of-software-engineering-as-a-profession&#34;&gt;The Death of Software Engineering as a Profession&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I was younger, I really liked programming! I loved the sense of accomplishment, I loved the problem solving, I loved sharing what I made with the people around me to both amuse and assist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One particularly wise adult (somewhere around 1996) took me aside and said, &amp;ldquo;You know, you&amp;rsquo;re lucky you &lt;em&gt;enjoy&lt;/em&gt; programming, because you won&amp;rsquo;t be able to make a living on it in the future. Doing it for love over money is a good idea.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Coding is over, with Object Oriented programming one person who is &lt;em&gt;much smarter than any of us could hope to be&lt;/em&gt; will develop the library just &lt;em&gt;once&lt;/em&gt; and we will all use it going forward, forever. Once a problem is solved it never needs solving again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;In 5 years there&amp;rsquo;s going to be a library of objects, like books on a bookshelf, and every software problem will be solved by business people just snapping the object libraries they need together like LEGOs. They won&amp;rsquo;t need you at all.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I thought about this advice, and how Software Engineering would be ending by the time I entered school. I realized I had not even thought about my education yet. I was in middle school. Programming was not it, though, I knew that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m here nearly 30 years later and software continues to pay my bills, despite everything. Open source exists, there are libraries I can use to piece things together to solve all the time. New problem sets not covered by the garden path come up all the time. Clicking the LEGOs together continues to be a hard task. Every time we fix it at one level of abstraction we operate one level higher and the world keeps turning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whenever I&amp;rsquo;m threatened with a good time and someone proclaims &amp;ldquo;this is it for you&amp;rdquo; all that happens is my job becomes more annoying. Haven&amp;rsquo;t gotten the sweet release of extinction quite yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-time-computing-changed-forever-and-everyone-who-didnt-move-got-left-behind&#34;&gt;The Time Computing Changed Forever and Everyone Who Didn&amp;rsquo;t Move Got Left Behind&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Around 1993 or so was the advent of the &amp;ldquo;Multimedia Age.&amp;rdquo; Multimedia was the buzzword. Software has to be &lt;em&gt;multimedia ready&lt;/em&gt;. Education had to teach children to be ready for &lt;em&gt;the multimedia age&lt;/em&gt;. If your tool, however inappropriate as it was, did not have multimedia features, you were going to be left behind. You &lt;em&gt;needed&lt;/em&gt; a video guide. You &lt;em&gt;needed&lt;/em&gt; to be on CD-ROM. This is just the new normal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Multimedia&amp;rdquo; just means &amp;ldquo;sound and video.&amp;rdquo; We had a high concept term for a very direct, low concept concept.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And the multimedia boom fizzled out. It became boring. Nobody is impressed by a video on a website and nobody thinks less of a website that doesn&amp;rsquo;t use sound and video if it&amp;rsquo;s not appropriate. You pop a &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;video /&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; tag in your HTML and your job is done. The amazing thing became mundane. The dream of &amp;ldquo;multimedia&amp;rdquo; became commonplace and everyone just accepted it as normal. I&amp;rsquo;m not aware of any industries that collapsed dramatically due to multimedia. Nobody really reskilled. Video editing is still a pretty rare skill, and we don&amp;rsquo;t commonly have sound engineers working on the audio UX of software products.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-death-of-software-engineering-as-a-profession-again&#34;&gt;The Death of Software Engineering as a Profession: Again&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2000 a coworker took me aside and showed me his brand-new copy of IntelliJ IDE. &amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s over for us,&amp;rdquo; he said, &amp;ldquo;this thing makes it so programmers aren&amp;rsquo;t strictly necessary, like one person can operate this tool and they can lay the rest of us off.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was pretty awestruck, he got some amazing autocomplete right in the IDE. Without having to have a separate JavaDocs window open to the side, and without having to manually open the page for the class he needed documentation on, it just was there inline. It gave him feedback before the compile cycle on a bunch of issues that you normally don&amp;rsquo;t see until build. That was a nice bit of preventative work and seemed to have the potential to keep a developer in flow longer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then he showed me the killer feature &amp;ldquo;that&amp;rsquo;s going to get us all out of a job:&amp;rdquo; the refactoring tools.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He then proceeded to show me the tools, easily moving around code to new files, renaming classes across the codebase, all kinds of manual things that would have taken a person a few days to do on their own. It was magical.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After some thought I said, &amp;ldquo;that&amp;rsquo;s amazing, but does it write new logic too or does it just move code around?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He didn&amp;rsquo;t seem fazed by that, and doubled down on the insistence that these powerful tools were our doom. I made a distinction between &amp;ldquo;useful&amp;rdquo; code and &amp;ldquo;filler&amp;rdquo; code, but apparently what is valued is not the quality and nature of the code but its volume and presence. This tool definitely gave both volume and presence to the tiny human-written nuggets within.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;that-time-i-automated-someone-out-of-a-job&#34;&gt;That Time I Automated Someone Out of a Job&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At my first job in High School I was working in an office in a suburban office park with programmers from many different local agencies. One guy I chatted up was a contractor: these people were highly regarded, somewhat feared specialists. The guy in question was working on a multi-year migration of some county health computer system from &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/MUMPS&#34;&gt;MUMPS&lt;/a&gt; to a more modern relational system. He showed me the main family of problems he was solving to show off how smart he was for solving them; they were largely rote problems of migrating table schemas and records in a pretty uniform way. But there were a lot of them, and he was working hard to meet his deadline!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I thought about it, and seeking his approval and validation, set out to help him. To show what I could do. I wrote a Python script that could solve the 85% case (it was mostly string manipulation) and even put a little TkInter dialog around it so he could select the files he wanted to migrate visually. It ran great, but he looked a little afraid when I demonstrated it to him:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;You didn&amp;rsquo;t show this to anyone else, did you?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Nope.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Oh thank God.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I take it he used my tool because he had a lot more free time to goof off for the remaining six months of his contract. I don&amp;rsquo;t think he told anyone else what he had either, but I&amp;rsquo;m guessing that he had a lot more MUMPS migration contracts lined up when he could finish them in a matter of days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;that-time-i-automated-myself-out-of-a-job&#34;&gt;That Time I Automated Myself Out of a Job&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the same job, I was paid to maintain a series of government agency web sites. One of my main tasks was to keep a list of mental health providers up-to-date on an HTML page and upload it to the server.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This process was pretty mechanical: take Excel sheet from inbox, open in Excel, copy Excel table to HTML table.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Within a month I had a fully automated workflow:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I used Windows Automation to watch my Outlook inbox&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When an email came in from the person who sent me the Excels it would download it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open the Excel file in excel using Windows Automation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Export it to CSV from Excel (the automation did this, I simply watched a ghost remote control an Excel window that opened and closed itself)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Run a Python script that would inject that CSV data as an HTML table into the file&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Run another Python script that would connect to the FTP server and upload the file. It would randomly pause and issue typos so it looked like the FTP session was being operated by a human at a keyboard so nobody thought anything on my plot.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I lived in fear of being found out, and told no one that the thing I was getting paid to do was no longer being done by me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About 9 months later the department in question hired a full-time web developer for $45k/yr to bring their website in-house. I was costing them about $25/hr, probably skating under $2000/yr for my outsourced services. This was clearly not about money.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And what I feared did not happen. When I no longer had that work to sustain me my managers just put me on something else.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s always more work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;we-dont-engage-in-theft&#34;&gt;We Don&amp;rsquo;t Engage in Theft&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my last years of undergraduate education and my first couple of years out of college I worked on projects that did some sort of Natural Language Processing tasks. For these we required training data, and the more the better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On that, though, we had responsibilities. We had to make sure the data we had also came with some sort of license or implicit permission. You didn&amp;rsquo;t just steal a pile of PDFs or scoop up a person&amp;rsquo;s web site and put it in your training set. There were ethical constrains, and legal consequences. You acted above-board when training your AI models.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There were times we&amp;rsquo;d train models on Wikipedia dumps. They were always comparatively &lt;em&gt;amazing&lt;/em&gt; results when we trained on good, large data like that. Cogent. Interesting. Even a simple Markov chain on Wikipedia looked smart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we wrote web crawlers, we wrote them to respect &lt;code&gt;robots.txt&lt;/code&gt;. We kept them on local domains. The &lt;code&gt;user-agent&lt;/code&gt; field of the crawlers included our email address, and if an angry webmaster didn&amp;rsquo;t like the way we were crawling them we&amp;rsquo;d fix it. Getting crawled aggressively at once taxed servers and spammed logs so we&amp;rsquo;d space it out to hours or days. If their &lt;code&gt;robots.txt&lt;/code&gt; was missing or malformed and they still didn&amp;rsquo;t want us there, we&amp;rsquo;d block the site from crawling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We made sure we had explicit permission to collect data for our training corpora.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-time-computing-changed-forever-and-everyone-who-didnt-move-got-left-behind-again&#34;&gt;The Time Computing Changed Forever and Everyone Who Didn&amp;rsquo;t Move Got Left Behind, Again&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The dot com boom was a crazy time. The internet has just become mainstream and there was a new gold rush. Money was there just for the taking, so many VC funded business plans were just &amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;traditional business X, but on the internet!&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo; and the money &lt;em&gt;flowed&lt;/em&gt;. How it flowed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of these companies, however, didn&amp;rsquo;t really have a solid business model other than buying some servers and a domain name and &amp;ldquo;we&amp;rsquo;ll put this thing on the internet.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Out of this crash came green shoots: Web 2.0, which used the web natively, organically, gave a good web-native experience. Eventually the dream of the internet, the promise of the hype, was made manifest after a lot of people learned a lot of really unnecessary, really painful lessons. They spent less and put their things on the internet because they made sense on the internet of the present, not because the internet was the next big thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The dream of the widespread, ubiquitous internet came true, and there were very few fatalities. Some businesses died, but it was more glacial than volcanic in time scale. When ubiquitous online services became commonplace it just felt mundane. It didn&amp;rsquo;t feel forced. It was the opposite of the dot com boom just five years later: &lt;em&gt;the internet is here and we&amp;rsquo;re here to build a solid business within it&lt;/em&gt; in contrast with &lt;em&gt;we should put this solid business on the internet somehow, because it&amp;rsquo;s coming&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;closing&#34;&gt;Closing&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is indeed a set of passive-aggressive jabs on the continuing assault on our senses by the LLM hype lobby.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><category domain="https://www.jasonscheirer.com//tags/llm">llm</category>
      <category domain="https://www.jasonscheirer.com//tags/work">work</category>
      <category domain="https://www.jasonscheirer.com//tags/life">life</category>
      <category domain="https://www.jasonscheirer.com//tags/programming">programming</category>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Classicube at Work</title>
      <link>https://www.jasonscheirer.com/weblog/playing-classicube-at-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2024 08:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jasonscheirer.com/weblog/playing-classicube-at-work/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;problem-space&#34;&gt;Problem Space&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.academia.edu/&#34;&gt;my new job&lt;/a&gt;, my new team engages in a team activity: every other week we get together for 30 minutes to play a game together online. We&amp;rsquo;re mixed hybrid, meaning about half of us work in office and half of us are grandfathered/exceptioned in to working remotely. this means we can&amp;rsquo;t play a board/card game in person, but has to be procurable over the internet in a Zoom call.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is now my turn to host a game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;picking-a-game&#34;&gt;Picking a Game&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m sure everyone is tired of playing Werewolf and variants at this point. I wanted something easy to pick up in the spirit of the games we&amp;rsquo;ve played on game days since I joined:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Casual&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Multiplayer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Browser-based&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Very low barrier to entry&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t want to pick Yet Another Card Game. That sounds boring.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;minecraft&#34;&gt;Minecraft?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/@ActionRetro&#34;&gt;One retro YouTuber I like&lt;/a&gt; pretty consistently plays &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.classicube.net/&#34;&gt;ClassiCube&lt;/a&gt; on the hardware devices he features in his videos. This seemed like a pretty good option: lower software requirements then MC Java Edition, as well as not requiring a paid account to play. It even &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.classicube.net/server/play/&#34;&gt;has a browser-based client&lt;/a&gt; that can connect to servers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ClassiCube/ClassiCube/blob/master/doc/hosting-flask.md&#34;&gt;ClassiCube has documentation on Github for how to run a browser-based session&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This seems pretty easy: you host a web page that has the ClassiCube JS client on it, and then configure it via Javascript in the page&amp;rsquo;s code to connect to your hosted server.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;of-course-i-have-to-write-software-to-run-software-it-is-my-wont&#34;&gt;Of Course I Have To Write Software to Run Software, It is My Wont&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The end product I made was &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jasonbot/cube-with-friends&#34;&gt;Cube With Friends on Github&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s a very easy to set up little program that does all the above manual steps &amp;ndash; at build time it embeds all the resources it needs from the internet into a single Go executable, and has other niceness like overlaying a pre-authored config that turns off ClassiCube authentication so people can join without having ClassiCube accounts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;getting-to-it-from-other-computers&#34;&gt;Getting to It From Other Computers&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that I had something running, how do I get other players on here?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I spun up &lt;code&gt;cube-with-friends&lt;/code&gt; on my laptop and started thinking my way through that problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;hosting-on-the-internet&#34;&gt;Hosting on the Internet&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t want to sacrifice one of my Raspberry Pis to be a permanent host for this app, and I&amp;rsquo;m not going to mess with seeing if I can get to the public IP that my ISP assigns me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t want to spin up a new VM on GCP and assign it a Real Internet IP Address and do all the work of exposing a service to the world if I can help it either.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;hosting-on-tailnet&#34;&gt;Hosting on Tailnet&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here comes an idea: my employer pays for a Tailscale corporate account, and all of our dev machines belong to the work tailnet. This is good, I can just point everyone to my work Mac.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;i-dont-want-to-put-a-personal-device-on-the-work-tailnet&#34;&gt;I Don&amp;rsquo;t Want to Put a Personal Device on the Work Tailnet&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My Raspberry Pi Collection has begun to dwindle, and I am not a fan of putting personal devices on work networks anyway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;my-work-mac-has-a-firewall-i-cant-disable&#34;&gt;My Work Mac Has a Firewall I Can&amp;rsquo;t Disable&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As is corporate policy, all of our work laptops have a firewall we can&amp;rsquo;t turn off. I can run Cube with Friends locally but the TCP ports are blocked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;i-dont-want-to-ask-the-infra-team-how-to-host-a-minecraft-server-thats-embarrassing&#34;&gt;I Don&amp;rsquo;t Want to ask the Infra Team How to Host a Minecraft Server, That&amp;rsquo;s Embarrassing&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I could host a machine on the Tailnet on our corporate Infrastructure, but I&amp;rsquo;m not on the infra team and I don&amp;rsquo;t know how to do that. I also don&amp;rsquo;t think I&amp;rsquo;d get buy-in for that. I&amp;rsquo;ll save my goodwill for some other day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;running-a-non-firewalled-machine-how-about-linux&#34;&gt;Running a Non-Firewalled Machine: How About Linux?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;rub-some-docker-on-it&#34;&gt;Rub Some Docker on It&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I quickly threw together a preliminary Dockerfile to make an image of a cube-with-friends instance, and started making progress. Now how to get it on the Tailnet?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://tailscale.com/kb/1453/quick-guide-docker&#34;&gt;This guide to using docker-compose to make a container join a Tailnet&lt;/a&gt; made me very sad at the complexity involved, but hopeful. I could run a Docker container on Linux, have the container join the Tailnet, and it would not be subject to the macOS firewall on the hardware network interfaces.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I switched from Docker Desktop to &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/abiosoft/colima&#34;&gt;Colima&lt;/a&gt; a few years back &amp;ndash; I&amp;rsquo;ve been moving away from using brand named Docker utils for a while now since 1) Docker has a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.docker.com/pricing/&#34;&gt;weird licensing tripwire&lt;/a&gt; I don&amp;rsquo;t want to set off and 2) &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/containers/&#34;&gt;containers are just a commodity&lt;/a&gt; in 2024 &amp;ndash; I use Podman on all my Linux machines to do containerization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Colima just works, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/abiosoft/colima?tab=readme-ov-file#runtimes&#34;&gt;has multiple personalities&lt;/a&gt; which was useful at my last job for dicking about with k8s and stuff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;colima-is-short-for-containers-on-lima&#34;&gt;CoLima is Short for &amp;ldquo;Containers on Lima&amp;rdquo;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/lima-vm/lima&#34;&gt;The Lima Project&lt;/a&gt; implements the underlying functionality of running a Linux VM on macOS that can then host the containers, since containers require &lt;a href=&#34;https://lwn.net/Articles/236038/&#34;&gt;Linux kernel internals&lt;/a&gt; to work (&lt;a href=&#34;https://wiki.freebsd.org/Containers&#34;&gt;or not&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why not short-circuit the process and just use the VM directly? Why bother with another abstraction layer? I&amp;rsquo;ll just use Lima directly and not make myself sad with the extra abstraction layer that a &lt;code&gt;compose&lt;/code&gt;-based solution im-&amp;hellip;poses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;starting-a-new-vm&#34;&gt;Starting a New VM&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cloned the repo &lt;code&gt;git clone git@github.com:jasonbot/cube-with-friends.git&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Started a new VM using &lt;code&gt;lima create default&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I edited the configuration so that my auto-mounted home drive was &lt;code&gt;writable: true&lt;/code&gt; before launching (this is important if you&amp;rsquo;re keeping the cloned repo on your Mac home dir and not on the VM)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Installed prereqs: &lt;code&gt;sudo apt install golang mono-runtime&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ran &lt;code&gt;lima&lt;/code&gt; to get into the VM&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Edited the &lt;code&gt;/etc/hostname&lt;/code&gt; to something memorable&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Restarted the VM&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Went back in via &lt;code&gt;lima&lt;/code&gt; and Installed Tailscale via &lt;code&gt;curl -fsSL https://tailscale.com/install.sh | sh&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Signed in to tailscale &lt;code&gt;sudo tailscale up&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ran the cube-with-friends server: &lt;code&gt;go run cmd/server.go&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Opened a browser to &lt;code&gt;http://my-new-machine:5555/&lt;/code&gt; and verified it worked&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So there we go! Something a little more interesting than playing another card game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.jasonscheirer.com/images/playing-classicube-at-work/ss1.png&#34; alt=&#34;Login Screen&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.jasonscheirer.com/images/playing-classicube-at-work/ss2.png&#34; alt=&#34;Success &amp;ndash; logged in&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;/p&gt;
</description><category domain="https://www.jasonscheirer.com//tags/programming">programming</category>
      <category domain="https://www.jasonscheirer.com//tags/work">work</category>
      <category domain="https://www.jasonscheirer.com//tags/golang">golang</category>
      <category domain="https://www.jasonscheirer.com//tags/minecraft">minecraft</category>
      <category domain="https://www.jasonscheirer.com//tags/games">games</category>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Job #1 of Codebases is Onboardability</title>
      <link>https://www.jasonscheirer.com/weblog/onboardable-codebases/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2024 00:55:10 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jasonscheirer.com/weblog/onboardable-codebases/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I got my first job as a software engineer in 2000, so in 2024 I&amp;rsquo;m pushing a quarter century of being a developer. This is one of the topics I have begun to hold near and dear to my heart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Software engineering is a team sport. If you&amp;rsquo;re not setting new players up for success, you&amp;rsquo;re not being the best teammate you could be. Supporting others is just as important as getting your needs met.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;absolute first goal&lt;/em&gt; of your codebase is to make it easy to get up and running for a new developer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;good-getting-started-resources&#34;&gt;Good Getting Started Resources&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your codebase &lt;em&gt;must&lt;/em&gt; have a base readme file with a getting started guide. It must be simple but comprehensive and step-by-step. This must also be kept up-to-date. It should be opinionated. &amp;ldquo;You can do it this way or this other way&amp;rdquo; is only going to spawn a &amp;ldquo;well which way should I do it?????&amp;rdquo; conversation in Slack. If you spend an hour a month grooming this document it will save you person-weeks a month in pairing sessions getting a new developer up and running. It is disrespectful to yourself and others&amp;rsquo; time to be proud enough to think your code is &amp;ldquo;special&amp;rdquo; or you can&amp;rsquo;t be bothered to engage in some form of service to your peers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;good-documentation-on-the-deep-stuff&#34;&gt;Good Documentation on the &amp;ldquo;Deep&amp;rdquo; Stuff&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Code gains complexity, complexity is the demon that makes code unmaintainable. By forcing developers to explain (in documentation) their decisions you 1) make them concrete and force them to be justified (code complete is not complete) 2) throttle developers who code for the sake of coding and make them explain why they did what they did (aside from the wrong reason &amp;ldquo;I like coding&amp;rdquo;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;organizational-conventions&#34;&gt;Organizational Conventions&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every codebase in the organization should follow conventions so that a new developer is able to get rudimentarily started without any prior knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Convention means that skills learned in one place can continue to be used elsewhere, and reduce cognitive load on remembering project-specific quirks when one is in e.g. a firefighting situation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I worked at Nerdwallet, we had this to an absurd degree with our internal tool &lt;code&gt;indy&lt;/code&gt;. You could &lt;code&gt;indy get&lt;/code&gt; a repo, &lt;code&gt;indy build&lt;/code&gt; to produce a deployable artifact, &lt;code&gt;indy test&lt;/code&gt; to run test suites, etc. This was regardless of stack or language, if you were not a Go or Node developer you could still use your &lt;code&gt;indy&lt;/code&gt; knowledge to get up and running in a repo in an unfamiliar stack.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Usually this is done via Makefiles in most startups I work in. Make sure you have common &lt;code&gt;{install,build,test,run}&lt;/code&gt; targets in every repo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;local-development-is-not-optional&#34;&gt;Local Development Is Not Optional&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your employer has given you a tremendously powerful laptop. It makes sense so utilize that hardware, and by keeping the running code close to the developer it makes it easier to instrument the code, start and stop individual components in the case of a constellation of services, and more effectively enter feedback loops and end-to-end development in an emotionally secure environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;end&#34;&gt;End&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t care how &amp;ldquo;complex&amp;rdquo; your needs are, your code is not special. You owe the respect to the people around you to make it possible (and, with empathy, &lt;em&gt;easy&lt;/em&gt;) to get started on your team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TL;DR&lt;/strong&gt; Say &lt;a href=&#34;https://microsoft.github.io/code-with-engineering-playbook/developer-experience/&#34;&gt;DevEx&lt;/a&gt; without saying DevEx.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.jasonscheirer.com/images/onboardable-codebases/build-process.png&#34; alt=&#34;Onboardable Codebases Meme&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;/p&gt;
</description><category domain="https://www.jasonscheirer.com//tags/work">work</category>
      <category domain="https://www.jasonscheirer.com//tags/programming">programming</category>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Framework Syndrome: Solving Software Problems by Not Solving Them</title>
      <link>https://www.jasonscheirer.com/weblog/framework-syndrome/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 19:55:10 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jasonscheirer.com/weblog/framework-syndrome/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A common antipattern I&amp;rsquo;ve been both perpetrator of and victim to is what I describe as &lt;em&gt;Framework Syndrome&lt;/em&gt;. This is the act of writing software that does not solve the inherent problem at hand, but provides a poorly designed scaffold in which one is expected to eventually &amp;ldquo;fill in the blanks.&amp;rdquo; That is, in the absence of the ability or desire to make the code do what it needs to do, kick the can down the road while at the same time writing mountains of not particularly useful code that will never be fully excised from the codebase.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;you-dont-understand-the-problem-so-you-code-around-it&#34;&gt;You Don&amp;rsquo;t Understand the Problem, So You Code Around It&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was 2005. I was working on an early SaaS product for automating Intro to Statistical Methods courses for Psychology undergraduates. We had a few functional requirements that I could do easily (user generation, logins, survey generators) and others I simply did not have the ability to do well (namely, actually do the statistical analysis that the grant required). So I worked around it. I added support to slice and dice data and export to Excel. I added natural language date parsing for forms. I polished the hell out of the admin interface. &amp;ldquo;This system is perfect,&amp;rdquo; I declared, &amp;ldquo;we just need someone to plug in the code to do that one thing it was designed to do: statistical methods. You just need to drop it in&amp;hellip;here. See how elegant it is?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;it-can-do-anything-you-just-have-to-provide-the-code&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;It Can Do Anything, You Just Have to Provide the Code&amp;rdquo;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Code that does not solve the problem, but provides an environment to add code that solves the problem, is ridiculous on its face. It&amp;rsquo;s just another level of abstraction that was added for the sake of engaging in the act of coding and not taking into mind any practical or business concerns.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;youve-done-the-fun-part-and-gotten-the-credit-someone-else-does-the-actual-work&#34;&gt;You&amp;rsquo;ve Done the &amp;ldquo;Fun&amp;rdquo; Part and Gotten The Credit, Someone Else Does the Actual Work&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the unfair part of Framework Syndrome, and something that makes me deeply resentful when I run into it. A developer who arrives at the project first &amp;ldquo;designs&amp;rdquo; a solution, runs it past management, declares it Mission Complete, and moves on. The person who has to work within the constraints established by that long-gone person does the actual work that adds the business value, and is ignored by management.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;a-skills-gap-in-architecture-design&#34;&gt;A Skills Gap in Architecture Design&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is not an argument against software architecture or architects. However, there tends to be a very drastic difference in a developer doing &lt;em&gt;speculative architecture&lt;/em&gt; without thinking the problem through and a more skilled, formal process of &lt;em&gt;anticipatory architecture&lt;/em&gt; that is required for a cohesive system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;let-the-implementors-do-the-framework-clean-up-later&#34;&gt;Let The Implementors do the Framework, Clean Up Later&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From the resentment part of the section above, I propose that software be written in the following way:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Prototype written by domain expert as messy code&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Professional engineers clean it up, finding common patterns across codebases and standardizing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By inverting the process from framework to solution to solution to framework, the frameworks themselves will be far more appropriate to the solutions they encompass.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><category domain="https://www.jasonscheirer.com//tags/work">work</category>
      <category domain="https://www.jasonscheirer.com//tags/programming">programming</category>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The 2020s and the Post-Office World</title>
      <link>https://www.jasonscheirer.com/weblog/the-post-office-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Feb 2021 07:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jasonscheirer.com/weblog/the-post-office-world/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I moved to the Bay Area 6 years ago after stubbornly refusing to for over a decade before because I wanted to be in the middle of the world of software. 2020 made some of that luster wear off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our office closed at the end of March, 2020, for what was scheduled to be 2 months, which eventually stretched out into over 6 months, until finally we were told to clean off our desks by Thanksgiving as we were permanently remote.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did poorly doing remote work in 2012 when I first tried it and didn&amp;rsquo;t look forward to doing it again. A big part of my day was framed around a commute, a large part of my productivity are 3 minute snippets of conversation with random people on the elevator to get an idea for what I could provide my coworkers, the majority of my socialization is in the context of work, and a large part of my sanity was my enthusiasm for figuring out byzantine ways to get around solely by public transit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Working from home has been varied as I adjust to it and go through cycles of acceptance, as well as the variance in the openness of the Bay Area. At one point places were open, which was great, and appointment based, which was even better because there was limited admittance and things were empty enough to appreciate in a way we hadn&amp;rsquo;t before. The SF and Oakland Zoos, 2 of my kid&amp;rsquo;s favorite places, were noticeably better experiences until they locked down and shut again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that I&amp;rsquo;m adjusting to working from home I am noting probably the same things everyone else is: that work/home boundaries are hard, that having a dedicated workspace is essential, and keeping a routine &lt;em&gt;with good sleep hygiene&lt;/em&gt; is absolutely paramount to not breaking down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A benefit of the events of 2020 was that I lost over 40 pounds &amp;ndash; no more being too tired to cook 3 nights a week and ordering out. No more eating a $20 lunch in the Financial District at a restaurant every day. No more cocktails on Fridays.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another benefit was saving money &amp;ndash; hundreds of dollars a month in eating out, hundreds of dollars in gas, hundreds of dollars on my Clipper card, hundreds of dollars in things like movie tickets and indoor playground fees. With that we were able to save more aggressively, and with our extra time able to do paperwork and visit house showings, so we were able to pounce and buy a home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was a little reluctant to buy a home in the Bay Area initially because &amp;ldquo;everyone is leaving,&amp;rdquo; but exoduses have happened here before and I honestly don&amp;rsquo;t anticipate things will stay like this forever, at the worst we&amp;rsquo;ll have to wait a decade. Our lifestyles won&amp;rsquo;t go entirely back to 2019, but people like living in cities and having interesting things to do nearby, and I&amp;rsquo;m sure even if the lucky Millennials who can afford it are permanently committing to the suburbs the next generation will cycle back and flock back to major cities and their surroundings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My new office is my garage &amp;ndash; we&amp;rsquo;re going to put in the money to turn it into a mock office, complete with a sealed &amp;ldquo;phone booth&amp;rdquo; room and cubicle-like partitions. Right now, it&amp;rsquo;s just a garage with a couple of desks that I share with the Christmas decorations, but it&amp;rsquo;s somewhere where my work life is separate from my home life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s been weird, but it&amp;rsquo;s been weird for everyone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Update 2021-02-10&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.wired.com/story/the-secret-essential-geography-of-the-office/&#34;&gt;This essay by Paul Ford&lt;/a&gt; covers a lot of my thinking about the office, too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Update 2021-03-27&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/cafedujord/status/1375255355962261504&#34;&gt;This tweet&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.jasonscheirer.com/images/the-post-office-world/tweet.png&#34; alt=&#34;This toot&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;/p&gt;
</description><category domain="https://www.jasonscheirer.com//tags/work">work</category>
      <category domain="https://www.jasonscheirer.com//tags/life">life</category>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Own Your Infrastructure</title>
      <link>https://www.jasonscheirer.com/weblog/own-your-infrastructure/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2020 16:45:45 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jasonscheirer.com/weblog/own-your-infrastructure/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been sharecropping on Amazon&amp;rsquo;s server farms since I moved to the Bay Area 5 years ago. That is, every startup I&amp;rsquo;ve worked for has utilized AWS (and sometimes GCP or Azure in addition).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This started out great for my career because I have not built a server machine from parts out since I was in college and I could use all my developer muscles to be operations person.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, when you&amp;rsquo;re on-call, you no longer own your uptime. Amazon will randomly flip bits. Its hosted services will go down without warning and leave you helpless but to wait &amp;ndash; you&amp;rsquo;re down until Amazon Hosted Whatever Thing decides to go back up (and the status page will lie about it being up).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now I&amp;rsquo;m at a new place where the systems team (I am back in plain old Software Engineering, hopefully out of DevOps forever) actually runs data centers. Everything is done in VMs and not containers. And it&amp;rsquo;s so refreshing. Not only can we be 100% responsible for fixing downtime, but it provides a much stabler and less abstract system to build software on top of. When the solution to a problem is &amp;ldquo;this Bash script&amp;rdquo; and not &amp;ldquo;this Byzantine pipeline only one guy understands&amp;rdquo; it makes the infrastructure easier to reason about and less prone to failure.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><category domain="https://www.jasonscheirer.com//tags/programming">programming</category>
      <category domain="https://www.jasonscheirer.com//tags/hardware">hardware</category>
      <category domain="https://www.jasonscheirer.com//tags/work">work</category>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python Meetup Talk - 2019-10-09</title>
      <link>https://www.jasonscheirer.com/weblog/python-meetup-sf-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2019 10:18:17 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jasonscheirer.com/weblog/python-meetup-sf-2019/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I gave a short (~10) minute talk on &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/jasonbot/python-meetup-2019-10-09&#34;&gt;preparing to move to microservices&lt;/a&gt; at the Python meetup in San Francisco.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main points:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We all start out with a monolith&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The monolith never fully goes away&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s fine&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Scope out a new project to make your first microservice&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pull out a relatively isolated piece of code in the monolith to make your next microservice&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description><category domain="https://www.jasonscheirer.com//tags/python">python</category>
      <category domain="https://www.jasonscheirer.com//tags/work">work</category>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What I Like About My New Job</title>
      <link>https://www.jasonscheirer.com/weblog/things-i-like-about-my-new-job/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 May 2015 19:55:10 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jasonscheirer.com/weblog/things-i-like-about-my-new-job/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is &lt;a href=&#34;https://jason.cleanstick.net/post/118755320730/things-i-like-about-my-new-job&#34;&gt;a recycled post from my tumblr weblog&lt;/a&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;ve since had three other jobs, but a lot of what I like still rings true 5 years later in 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please note I am contractually prohibited from saying what I &lt;em&gt;don&amp;rsquo;t&lt;/em&gt; like about most of my prior employers so don&amp;rsquo;t expect any negative posts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve gone from developer at a large software corporation in the suburbs of Southern California to being a developer at a startup in SoMa in San Francisco. I&amp;rsquo;ve been here about three months now and this is a list of (some) of the things I like about my new job.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Continuous Integration&lt;/strong&gt;: This is something that I took for granted almost a decade ago at a former employer and haven&amp;rsquo;t had since. When I make a change and push it to GitHub, a set of tests automatically spin up and I can&amp;rsquo;t merge to master until those tests pass. This is good, I have a self-service QA agent where I can iteratively work on an issue and finally do a PR when it&amp;rsquo;s ready.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Actual Decent Test Coverage&lt;/strong&gt;: There&amp;rsquo;s a test suite built in to the code, not saved as an auxiliary repository. When the codebase has a decent set of tests it helps you make sure your changes don&amp;rsquo;t break anything, and it also works to make you feel guilty if you aren&amp;rsquo;t keeping the coverage levels up with your new code, creating a virtuous cycle of test writing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Code Reviews that Actually Happen&lt;/strong&gt;: The tooling for deploys is set up so that no code can be merged into the master branch until it gets a code review/thumbs up by at least one other non-author developer. Code can&amp;rsquo;t be checked in, period, unless it&amp;rsquo;s been hit by at least two sets of eyes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You Can Ship a Feature Same-Day&lt;/strong&gt;: Assuming the feature is small enough, you could sit down at 9:00 AM, implement a feature, write tests, get it code reviewed and have the code shipping by 5:00 PM to real live clients. It was frustrating waiting 16+ months to ship features/fixes at the last place, it&amp;rsquo;s refreshing to get immediate feedback on my work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The CTO/Cofounder Still Writes Code&lt;/strong&gt;: Certainly he doesn&amp;rsquo;t write the same volume of code he did when there were 4 developers, but the fact that the CTO still finds time to write code/add features to the product shows upper management actually cares about what&amp;rsquo;s under the hood of the product.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;No Silos&lt;/strong&gt;: There are functional teams, and there are specialists, but for the most part everyone works transparently. Meeting notes from each meeting go to an email alias everyone is subscribed to, all GitHub repos are accessible by every engineer, if you want to know how something works all you have to do is look.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Up-to-Date Documents&lt;/strong&gt;: We use a Wiki and we&amp;rsquo;ve got people engaged enough and motivated enough to tend to it like a garden. No 5-year-old Word documents hiding as sharepoint attachments that require you to ask 5 people to see what&amp;rsquo;s no longer true/correct. If anyone finds a set of instructions confusing on a page, they go in and change it so they&amp;rsquo;re less confusing/more correct for the next person, which leads to the next point:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If Something&amp;rsquo;s Broken, You Don&amp;rsquo;t Need Permission to Fix It&lt;/strong&gt;: We get used to little and big annoyances in every software product we use. When I first started I was a little timid about suggesting fixes, figuring things were the way they were for a reason. I&amp;rsquo;m learning now that I can fix annoyances with impunity—nobody gets mad if you make the software better, even if it&amp;rsquo;s in code you wouldn&amp;rsquo;t normally be responsible for. They&amp;rsquo;re thankful, in fact. We&amp;rsquo;ve just begun to formalize this in &amp;lsquo;Spring Cleaning:&amp;rsquo; one day a month we just work on back burner/wish list items. And it&amp;rsquo;s fun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If You Want to Do More, Do More&lt;/strong&gt;: This is fairly straightforward: if you want to learn something new, go ahead and do it. If you want to be responsible for X, start working on X. No need for formal requests or transfers. As a riff on the above, if you want to do it, do it. This is a fantastic way to work and makes it possible to do professional development in all sorts of directions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Public Transportation&lt;/strong&gt;: This is more a living in the Bay Area thing. In Redlands my strategy for making a painless commute was to live as close as possible to work. Now my strategy is to just live near a train station. My commute from near SFO up to the Caltrain station in SF is about 25 minutes most mornings. In that time I can read or use my laptop, rather than feather my clutch in stop-and-go traffic and scream at other drivers. It&amp;rsquo;s nice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Officially Sanctioned Social Events&lt;/strong&gt;: Hearsay Social puts on little social events all the time. It&amp;rsquo;s the best way to learn what other people are up to and to form bonds outside of meetings and email. It&amp;rsquo;s really nice getting to know your coworkers in this manner and makes things smoother while actually working together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Unofficially Sanctioned Social Events&lt;/strong&gt;: A lot of people have common interests and like each other enough to organize small group activities. Some people do rock climbing or go to amusement parks or do a weekly board game night. It&amp;rsquo;s pretty great.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The People&lt;/strong&gt;: As a San Francisco tech startup, the people skew a little younger than I&amp;rsquo;m used to, but everyone is smart and reasonable and easy to talk to. There&amp;rsquo;s no &amp;ldquo;watch out for that guy&amp;rdquo; warnings because there are no &amp;ldquo;that guy&amp;quot;s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All in all I&amp;rsquo;m glad I came up and I&amp;rsquo;m happy with Hearsay Social.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><category domain="https://www.jasonscheirer.com//tags/work">work</category>
      <category domain="https://www.jasonscheirer.com//tags/life">life</category>
      
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
