<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>hardware on Jason Scheirer</title>
    <link>https://www.jasonscheirer.com/tags/hardware/</link>
    <description>Recent content in hardware on Jason Scheirer</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 05:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.jasonscheirer.com/tags/hardware/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>ZPL-O-Rama Part 5: Postscript</title>
      <link>https://www.jasonscheirer.com/weblog/zpl-o-rama-part-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jasonscheirer.com/weblog/zpl-o-rama-part-5/</guid>
      <description>End product Please disregard the poor camera placement or the labels, it has since been fixed.
Thinking Back, It Was All So Simple Now we have the system up and running, let&amp;rsquo;s talk random obstacles and next steps. This is something of an epilogue to the saga, as it&amp;rsquo;s a list of small things that accrued while working on the project.
Networks are slow and the dual tier service thing is bad, actually I initially chose to run a service on the Nginx server that then called to a service running on the RPi.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ZPL-O-Rama Part 4: The Hardware</title>
      <link>https://www.jasonscheirer.com/weblog/zpl-o-rama-part-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jasonscheirer.com/weblog/zpl-o-rama-part-4/</guid>
      <description>Hardware The RPi The Raspberry Pi is a (I think) Pi 3 with Wifi I found in the garage with a cheap clear acrylic case. It might have been a RetroPie rig in a prior life? Or one I was &amp;ldquo;gonna get around to&amp;rdquo; doing something with and finally did?
Then for this project I bought a Raspberry Pi camera and a small acrylic case for it, too.
The Printer The printer is a hefty boi, a Zebra something or other.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ZPL-O-Rama Part 2: Concepts and Architecture</title>
      <link>https://www.jasonscheirer.com/weblog/zpl-o-rama-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 02:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jasonscheirer.com/weblog/zpl-o-rama-part-2/</guid>
      <description>Problem Space To automate the process of printing and reporting back a ZPL payload, we need:
A way to get the ZPL from the user A way to send the ZPL to a printer A way to take a picture A way to send it back to the user A way to get the ZPL from the user A web service makes sense here. We want an API or a frontend (or both) to send the ZPL along and check its printing status.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ZPL-O-Rama Part 1: A personal/work project (Introduction)</title>
      <link>https://www.jasonscheirer.com/weblog/zpl-o-rama-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jasonscheirer.com/weblog/zpl-o-rama-part-1/</guid>
      <description>Introduction In my spare time on weekends in between errands and mornings before everyone wakes up, I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on a little project I&amp;rsquo;ve been having a lot of fun with: ZPL-O-Rama.
The Problem A large part of my employer&amp;rsquo;s line of business is creating shipping labels, and a large number of those aren&amp;rsquo;t simply printed images, but printed on very high volume, heavy duty, industrial grade printers using a proprietary language called ZPL.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Shanling Q1 Media Player</title>
      <link>https://www.jasonscheirer.com/weblog/shanling-q1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jasonscheirer.com/weblog/shanling-q1/</guid>
      <description>Introduction A while ago I was bored with the Mechanical Keyboard rabbit hole and started looking into other, equally strange rabbit holes to dive into. At around the same time I hit my iPod Classic&amp;rsquo;s 160GB limit. I&amp;rsquo;m not yet ready to hack it up to have bigger storage: I plan to keep it in working &amp;ldquo;original&amp;rdquo; condition as it may find a better home in the future with some collector who is better at soldering than I.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pinebook Pro: The Tinkering Laptop</title>
      <link>https://www.jasonscheirer.com/weblog/pinebook-pro-the-tinkering-laptop/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jan 2021 12:11:45 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jasonscheirer.com/weblog/pinebook-pro-the-tinkering-laptop/</guid>
      <description>As the parent of an almost three year old, I don&amp;rsquo;t get much time to myself, and I&amp;rsquo;ve given up on video games that don&amp;rsquo;t have playtimes under 15 minutes (that discounts anything with load times or cutscenes). In my spare time I have to find other things to do that are low impact and can be cut into small amounts of time.
I&amp;rsquo;ve taken to watching a lot of retrocomputing stuff on YouTube, which has inspired me to tinker with old software and resource constrained devices.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Dingus Chromebook still works</title>
      <link>https://www.jasonscheirer.com/weblog/chromebook-still-works/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2020 01:11:45 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jasonscheirer.com/weblog/chromebook-still-works/</guid>
      <description>So I bought that dang Chromebook over three years ago at this point and it keeps chugging on. Google has continued to ship OS updates (which I only notice as weird, arbitrary UI changes) and I can still use it to code but its main purpose now is its new life: ChromeOS runs Android apps pretty well, so I put an SD card full of movies on it and play them via VLC for my kid.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Own Your Infrastructure</title>
      <link>https://www.jasonscheirer.com/weblog/own-your-infrastructure/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2020 16:45:45 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jasonscheirer.com/weblog/own-your-infrastructure/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been sharecropping on Amazon&amp;rsquo;s server farms since I moved to the Bay Area 5 years ago. That is, every startup I&amp;rsquo;ve worked for has utilized AWS (and sometimes GCP or Azure in addition).
This started out great for my career because I have not built a server machine from parts out since I was in college and I could use all my developer muscles to be operations person.
However, when you&amp;rsquo;re on-call, you no longer own your uptime.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Turn a Chromebook into the ULTIMATE GOLANG/PYTHON DEVELOPER MACHINE</title>
      <link>https://www.jasonscheirer.com/weblog/make-a-chromebook-a-developer-machine/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Dec 2016 01:11:45 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jasonscheirer.com/weblog/make-a-chromebook-a-developer-machine/</guid>
      <description>This is a recycled post from my tumblr weblog
Ha ha ha just lying the real title should be
Turning a Piece of Shit Chromebook into a Good Enough Development Machine Because You&amp;rsquo;re Unemployed and Feel Like An Ass Trying to Justify Spending $2000 on a God Damned Macbook so You Wound Up Buying a Chromebook Instead Anyway, I&amp;rsquo;m unemployed because of reasons and figured there were better things to do with the credit limit on my credit card than spend $2000 on a Macbook, so I bought one of the highest rated Chromebooks at my &amp;ldquo;willing to pay this much&amp;rdquo; price point: the Chromebook C100P.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
