<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Writing on Jason Scheirer</title>
    <link>https://www.jasonscheirer.com/tags/writing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Writing on Jason Scheirer</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 May 2025 00:00:00 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.jasonscheirer.com/tags/writing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Kicking the Tires on Harper</title>
      <link>https://www.jasonscheirer.com/weblog/kicking-the-tires-on-harper/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 May 2025 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jasonscheirer.com/weblog/kicking-the-tires-on-harper/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m trying out the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Automattic/harper&#34;&gt;Harper&lt;/a&gt; tool &lt;a href=&#34;https://marketplace.visualstudio.com/items?itemName=elijah-potter.harper&#34;&gt;in VS Code&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been aware of its existence for about 6 months and didn&amp;rsquo;t think much of it, just another rehash of existing tools.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I&amp;rsquo;ve come around to the idea that rewriting old tools isn&amp;rsquo;t a horrible notion: the people who crafted them were no smarter or dumber than ourselves, they were just before us. Rewriting the same thing is a lot like repaving an old road: core infrastructure, but with new materials maybe we can do it better. If anything, we should share in some of the fun the people who came before us got to have.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, so far so good. It&amp;rsquo;s a little less annoying than piping my posts through &lt;code&gt;aspell&lt;/code&gt;, which is about as sophisticated as I&amp;rsquo;ve managed to get myself in this writing workflow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s nice. I thought it was too invasive and preachy on first use long ago, but this time around, at least on first shake, it&amp;rsquo;s just enough for grammar/spell smell testing. It can run ubiquitously as it builds to WASM and an LSP, so I can learn to lean on it in a wide variety of environments.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><category domain="https://www.jasonscheirer.com//tags/writing">writing</category>
      <category domain="https://www.jasonscheirer.com//tags/harper">harper</category>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Wrong Conclusion</title>
      <link>https://www.jasonscheirer.com/weblog/the-wrong-conclusion/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 May 2025 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jasonscheirer.com/weblog/the-wrong-conclusion/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A common pattern I have come to recognize everywhere as an anti-pattern:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Person starts a dialogue establishing a problem, upon which we all agree&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Person continues on down the same line of conversation, outlining a solution&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Person comes to a conclusion which is a call to action&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I see this a lot because step 1 seems to short-circuit the thinking behind the rest of the logic. You got a narrative going that you feel compelled to continue to listen to, and assume it&amp;rsquo;s only going to stay sane.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, &lt;strong&gt;just because you have identified a problem does not mean your solution is correct&lt;/strong&gt;. Stop yourself when a person opens a paragraph and remember that &lt;em&gt;where they are going is not necessarily the only path, or even a sensible one&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The example I see most currently is about AI somehow matching human intelligence, usually in the context of LLMs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;LLMs exist, and seem to have novel properties that mimic humans producing language&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Therefore, LLMs are the same as humans producing language&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Therefore, LLMs have all the other capacities of humans and have been endowed with human nature and will replace us all&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve decorated these talking points with some straw men that are usually left implicit when usually presented, but you get the idea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just because you agree with the problem statement does not mean that the conclusion is correct just because it occurs a few sentences later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ludic.mataroa.blog/blog/the-narrative-fallacy/&#34;&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s an interesting blog post elsewhere&lt;/a&gt; on narratives and being misleading as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description><category domain="https://www.jasonscheirer.com//tags/writing">writing</category>
      
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
