<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Writing on Jason Scheirer</title>
    <link>https://www.jasonscheirer.com/tags/writing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Writing on Jason Scheirer</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 00:08:00 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.jasonscheirer.com/tags/writing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>What You Do and Who You Are</title>
      <link>https://www.jasonscheirer.com/weblog/ser-estar/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 00:08:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jasonscheirer.com/weblog/ser-estar/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Similar to &lt;a href=&#34;../the-wrong-conclusion/&#34;&gt;The Wrong Conclusion&lt;/a&gt; is another cognitive anti-pattern: in the pursuit of identity we see ourselves as &lt;em&gt;being&lt;/em&gt; something as an inherent quality of ourselves versus &lt;em&gt;doing something&lt;/em&gt; as a role, a quality being temporarily practiced. This can lead to bad behavior on our part and it limits our ability to grow and engage in introspection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have this hard-won lesson over my lifetime: when I stake my identity as &lt;em&gt;being&lt;/em&gt; a thing, when I can no longer &lt;em&gt;do&lt;/em&gt; the thing I lose my sense of self and spiral into crisis. I &lt;em&gt;am&lt;/em&gt; a good programmer, so &lt;em&gt;I &lt;strong&gt;am&lt;/strong&gt; an entity only when &lt;strong&gt;I am programming&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I spend a week in the hospital, as I did a few years ago, I &lt;em&gt;am no longer programming&lt;/em&gt;. I have lost my anchor. This is upsetting! I need to find a better &lt;em&gt;I AM&lt;/em&gt; or accept that programming is an &lt;em&gt;I DO&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alternatively, I never really thought of myself as a future parent growing up. Then I had a kid! Whether I like it or not, I am a parent, and I &lt;em&gt;do&lt;/em&gt; parenting things &lt;em&gt;every day&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People who take moral stances often consider themselves to &lt;em&gt;be the good guys&lt;/em&gt;, a quality inherent in themselves, versus being people who happen to strive to &lt;em&gt;do the good thing&lt;/em&gt;. When you are tautologically good, this is bad! You can do evil but by definition you are &lt;em&gt;doing good because good is what you are&lt;/em&gt;. I see it in this quote:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Conservatism consists of exactly one proposition, to wit: There must be in-groups whom the law protects but does not bind, alongside out-groups whom the law binds but does not protect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Francis M. Wilhoit&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I see this as pithy but extremely cutting and insightful: if you cannot see what &lt;em&gt;you are doing is counter to your identity&lt;/em&gt;, you can be convinced that &lt;em&gt;what you are doing is inconsequential to your identity&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Going from an &lt;em&gt;I am&lt;/em&gt; to an &lt;em&gt;I do&lt;/em&gt; mindset has been a tough lesson for me, but it&amp;rsquo;s been transformative in my worldview. It is, in many ways, tied to a growth mindset versus a fixed mindset: (I am / I am only) and (I do / I can become) being very closely related. I don&amp;rsquo;t &amp;lsquo;consider myself&amp;rsquo; a Javascript Guy, for instance, but if &lt;em&gt;I make a presentation about some Javascript thing I researched and shared&lt;/em&gt; I have &lt;em&gt;done Javascript Guy things&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As far as this goes, back to the growth mindset: you are only alive so long as you are active, and there is plenty of life left in you to be active. You are not a (metaphoric) flag planted in the (metaphoric) ground, you have (metaphoric) legs and can (metaphorically) walk to the next (metaphoric) place. You are capable of cruelty and laziness, and you are capable of kindness and industry. You need to be constantly vigilant to make sure you &lt;em&gt;are currently doing good&lt;/em&gt; and do not rest on the laurels of &lt;em&gt;I once did good&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;I &lt;strong&gt;am&lt;/strong&gt; good so what I do is, by definition, good&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, these were a few short paragraphs summarizing a spiritual crisis I spent 4 years mulling over. Enjoy! Hope you learn the lesson the easy way (from the mistakes of others, namely your supremely handsome narrator) rather than the hard way (having your own mistakes serve as a warning to others).&lt;/p&gt;
</description><category domain="https://www.jasonscheirer.com//tags/writing">writing</category>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kicking the Tires on Harper</title>
      <link>https://www.jasonscheirer.com/weblog/kicking-the-tires-on-harper/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 May 2025 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jasonscheirer.com/weblog/kicking-the-tires-on-harper/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m trying out the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Automattic/harper&#34;&gt;Harper&lt;/a&gt; tool &lt;a href=&#34;https://marketplace.visualstudio.com/items?itemName=elijah-potter.harper&#34;&gt;in VS Code&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been aware of its existence for about 6 months and didn&amp;rsquo;t think much of it, just another rehash of existing tools.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I&amp;rsquo;ve come around to the idea that rewriting old tools isn&amp;rsquo;t a horrible notion: the people who crafted them were no smarter or dumber than ourselves, they were just before us. Rewriting the same thing is a lot like repaving an old road: core infrastructure, but with new materials maybe we can do it better. If anything, we should share in some of the fun the people who came before us got to have.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, so far so good. It&amp;rsquo;s a little less annoying than piping my posts through &lt;code&gt;aspell&lt;/code&gt;, which is about as sophisticated as I&amp;rsquo;ve managed to get myself in this writing workflow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s nice. I thought it was too invasive and preachy on first use long ago, but this time around, at least on first shake, it&amp;rsquo;s just enough for grammar/spell smell testing. It can run ubiquitously as it builds to WASM and an LSP, so I can learn to lean on it in a wide variety of environments.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><category domain="https://www.jasonscheirer.com//tags/writing">writing</category>
      <category domain="https://www.jasonscheirer.com//tags/harper">harper</category>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Wrong Conclusion</title>
      <link>https://www.jasonscheirer.com/weblog/the-wrong-conclusion/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 May 2025 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jasonscheirer.com/weblog/the-wrong-conclusion/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A common pattern I have come to recognize everywhere as an anti-pattern:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Person starts a dialogue establishing a problem, upon which we all agree&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Person continues on down the same line of conversation, outlining a solution&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Person comes to a conclusion which is a call to action&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I see this a lot because step 1 seems to short-circuit the thinking behind the rest of the logic. You got a narrative going that you feel compelled to continue to listen to, and assume it&amp;rsquo;s only going to stay sane.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, &lt;strong&gt;just because you have identified a problem does not mean your solution is correct&lt;/strong&gt;. Stop yourself when a person opens a paragraph and remember that &lt;em&gt;where they are going is not necessarily the only path, or even a sensible one&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The example I see most currently is about AI somehow matching human intelligence, usually in the context of LLMs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;LLMs exist, and seem to have novel properties that mimic humans producing language&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Therefore, LLMs are the same as humans producing language&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Therefore, LLMs have all the other capacities of humans and have been endowed with human nature and will replace us all&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve decorated these talking points with some straw men that are usually left implicit when usually presented, but you get the idea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just because you agree with the problem statement does not mean that the conclusion is correct just because it occurs a few sentences later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ludic.mataroa.blog/blog/the-narrative-fallacy/&#34;&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s an interesting blog post elsewhere&lt;/a&gt; on narratives and being misleading as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description><category domain="https://www.jasonscheirer.com//tags/writing">writing</category>
      
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
