<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>programming on Jason Scheirer</title>
    <link>https://www.jasonscheirer.com/tags/programming/</link>
    <description>Recent content in programming on Jason Scheirer</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Feb 2021 08:00:00 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.jasonscheirer.com/tags/programming/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>SFTP is still around and that&#39;s OK</title>
      <link>https://www.jasonscheirer.com/weblog/sftp-is-still-around-and-thats-ok/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Feb 2021 08:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jasonscheirer.com/weblog/sftp-is-still-around-and-thats-ok/</guid>
      <description>So it&amp;rsquo;s 2021 and about the entirety of my job is integrating third party systems with internal ones, which then reach out to other third-party services.
A lot of stuff uses SFTP still. In this day and age anything not on HTTP seems barbaric, but SFTP does have its advantages.
SFTP is format agnostic This goes for HTTP as well, but you need to correctly set headers, and there&amp;rsquo;s a constant, incessant push for change for change&amp;rsquo;s sake.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You Don&#39;t Need to Make That Temporary File, Dude</title>
      <link>https://www.jasonscheirer.com/weblog/dont-use-tempfiles/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Feb 2021 08:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jasonscheirer.com/weblog/dont-use-tempfiles/</guid>
      <description>This was initially a blog post I wrote on my employer&amp;rsquo;s internal system, but it&amp;rsquo;s interestingly useful and it doesn&amp;rsquo;t contain any trade secrets so I figure I&amp;rsquo;ll share.
 A common pattern that seems obvious when you need to shuttle data around in file form is to use a temporary file against the filesystem using the tempfile module.
You very seldom ACTUALLY need to do this. The BytesIO class follows the exact same protocol, the file protocol, so any API that accepts a &amp;ldquo;file-like object&amp;rdquo; will accept an in-memory piece of information in addition to a file on disk.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Own your infrastructure</title>
      <link>https://www.jasonscheirer.com/weblog/own-your-infrastructure/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2020 16:45:45 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jasonscheirer.com/weblog/own-your-infrastructure/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been sharecropping on Amazon&amp;rsquo;s server farms since I moved to the Bay Area 5 years ago. That is, every startup I&amp;rsquo;ve worked for has utilized AWS (and sometimes GCP or Azure in addition).
This started out great for my career because I have not built a server machine from parts out since I was in college and I could use all my developer muscles to be operations person.
However, when you&amp;rsquo;re on-call, you no longer own your uptime.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jumpbear: the Global Warming Bear</title>
      <link>https://www.jasonscheirer.com/weblog/jumpbear/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 May 2018 01:15:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jasonscheirer.com/weblog/jumpbear/</guid>
      <description>I wrote a handful of different things on my paternity leave, but one of the more interesting ones was this small TIC-80 game where you play a bear.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Turn a Chromebook into the ULTIMATE GOLANG/PYTHON DEVELOPER MACHINE</title>
      <link>https://www.jasonscheirer.com/weblog/make-a-chromebook-a-developer-machine/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Dec 2016 01:11:45 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jasonscheirer.com/weblog/make-a-chromebook-a-developer-machine/</guid>
      <description>This is a recycled post from my tumblr weblog
 Ha ha ha just lying the real title should be
Turning a Piece of Shit Chromebook into a Good Enough Development Machine Because You&amp;rsquo;re Unemployed and Feel Like An Ass Trying to Justify Spending $2000 on a God Damned Macbook so You Wound Up Buying a Chromebook Instead Anyway, I&amp;rsquo;m unemployed because of reasons and figured there were better things to do with the credit limit on my credit card than spend $2000 on a Macbook, so I bought one of the highest rated Chromebooks at my &amp;ldquo;willing to pay this much&amp;rdquo; price point: the Chromebook C100P.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>C&#43;&#43; is not so bad</title>
      <link>https://www.jasonscheirer.com/weblog/cpp-is-ok/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Sep 2010 16:45:45 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jasonscheirer.com/weblog/cpp-is-ok/</guid>
      <description>For as much shit as I like to talk about C++, I sure can get a lot done quite efficiently in it.
I read an interview with Bjarne a while back and he said C++’s most important feature was destructors. After thinking about it, yeah, they are pretty awesome and I’ve been using the with statement for the same tightly scoped data lifetime in Python.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I don’t really use OSX anymore</title>
      <link>https://www.jasonscheirer.com/weblog/osx-less-and-less/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Feb 2010 01:15:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.jasonscheirer.com/weblog/osx-less-and-less/</guid>
      <description>I have two desktop systems, side-by-side: an Intel Mac Mini and an Intel 21&amp;quot; iMac. The Mini runs Leopard and the iMac runs Ubuntu Karmic Koala, and I find myself completely satisfied with the Linux desktop, and switch back to OSX as an auxiliary rather than as my primary.
I started on Debian back in 1999. I wanted to get into Linux, but both Red Hat and SuSE were a little hard to get going for beginners, and the packages supplied were always a weird grab bag of old and new.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
